To End All Wars is a drama, war, action film directed by David L. Cunningham.
Based on a real-life story, this drama focuses on a small group of Allied
soldiers in Burma who are held captive by the Japanese.
Ernest Gordon, Lt.
Jim Reardon and Maj.
Ian Campbell are among the military officers kept imprisoned
and routinely beaten and deprived of food.
While Campbell wants to rebel and attempt an escape, Gordon tries to take a more
stoic approach, an attitude that proves to be surprisingly resonant.
Capt. Ernest Gordon, played by Ciarán McMenamin.
Major Ian Campbell, played by Robert Carlyle.
Lt. Jim 'Yanker' Reardon, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Dusty Miller, played by Mark Strong.
Takashi Nagase, played by Yugo Saso.
Sgt. Ito, played by Sakae Kimura.
To End All Wars is a 2001 war film starring Robert Carlyle, Kiefer
Sutherland and Sakae Kimura and was directed by David L.
Cunningham.
The film is based on Through the Valley of the Kwai, an autobiography of Ernest Gordon, then a
Scottish Captain, later the Presbyterian Dean of the Princeton University Chapel.
The film explores themes of japan, scotland,
traitor, world war ii, freight train.
The tone is emotional.